Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Campaign for Governor of Pennsylvania, 1978; IX.
  - News Releases, 2.
    - January-March, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 12)
      - Proposed that the PA Department of Environmental Resources (DER) be given a new role of providing business with technological advice in meeting environmental standards, Philadelphia, PA, March 15, 1978; 10.
      - Announced that he and his cabinet officers would hold town meetings in communities across PA once he became governor, Lancaster, PA, March 16, 1978; 11.
      - Outlined the leadership role and steps he would take as governor to "set PA on a confident path to a more stable future," Middletown, PA, March 17, 1978; 12.
      - Fundraising dinner for Dick Thornburgh will be held on Monday, March 27, in Philadelphia at the Franklin Institute with featured speaker, William D. Ruckelshaus, former Deputy Attorney General of the U.S. and FBI Director, March 22, 1978; 13.
      - Announced that he would establish a Small Business Advisory Committee to give small businessmen "greater access to the governor's office," Altoona, PA, March 23, 1978; 14.
      - Called on PA's General Assembly to immediately pass legislation that would require public officials who are convicted of crimes involving abuse of their office to forfeit their state pensions, Pittsburgh, PA, March 24, 1978; 15.
      - Called on President Carter to establish an office on anthracite coal within the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) as a means of "stimulating use of one of Northeast PA's most abundant natural resources," Scranton, PA, March 28, 1978; 16
      - The public is invited to two receptions next Tuesday, March 28, in Scranton and Wilkes-Barre for Dick Thornburgh, Republican candidate for governor, March 28, 1978; 17.
      - Fulfilled his campaign pledge to disclose campaign contributions, revealing that $409,803 has been contributed to his campaign through March 17, March 29, 1978; 18.
    - April, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 13)
      - A number of leading PA sportsmen have formed a Sportsmen for Thornburgh Committee in order to publicize Thornburgh's record as Assistant Attorney General and his efforts to preserve PA's waterways and woodlands, April 1, 1978; 1.
      - State Representative James Knepper said he found Butera's attempt to misrepresent Republican gubernatorial candidate Thornburgh's position on key issues while attempting to conceal his own, "deplorable", April 3, 1978; 2.
      - Public is invited to meet Thornburgh, Republican candidate for governor, at a reception April 8, Bushkill, PA, April 4, 1978; 3.
      - Said that PA must develop a comprehensive energy policy before creating any energy-related bureaucracies, as two bills pending in the legislature would do, Hershey, PA, April 4, 1978; 4.
      - "People's Fund Raiser" will be held tonight for Republican gubernatorial candidate Thornburgh by supporters in his hometown of Carnegie, PA, April 6, 1978; 5.
      - Thornburgh will announce his dramatic and comprehensive proposals for restoring PA's deteriorating highways and bridges tomorrow at site of Thornburg Bridge on Route 60, April 6, 1978; 6.
      - Summary of Dick Thornburgh's Highway and Bridge Program: "Facing Up to the Highway and Bridge Crisis in PA", April 7, 1978; 7.
      - Unveiled a comprehensive and innovative program for restoring PA's deteriorating bridges and highways, April 7, 1978; 8.
      - Will host a public "Farmers Town Meeting" in Lancaster with the agricultural community, April 8, 1978; 9.
      - Said that Northwest PA has been "ignored for too long by the decision-makers in Harrisburg," Warren, PA, April 10, 1978; 10.
      - Called on PA Senate and PA's state-supported colleges to open their past and present files on the senatorial scholarship system, Harrisburg, PA, April 11, 1978; 11.
      - Fundraising dinner for Thornburgh will be held April 18 in Hershey with featured speaker W. J. Usery, former U.S. Secretary of Labor, April 12, 1978; 13.
      - Schedule of campaign appearances for week of April 17 through April 22, April 14, 1978; 14.
      - Said that state government must give PA's Mayors a greater voice in state programs that affect their communities, Philadelphia, PA, April 17, 1978; 15.
      - Former U.S. Secretary of Labor W. J. Usery said that election as governor of Republican Dick Thornburgh would mean "a stable climate for business and labor, and economic growth for PA," Hershey, PA, April 18, 1978; 16.
      - State Representative James Knepper charged that statements by former House Speaker Kenneth B. Lee on behalf of Butera were "divisive and can only hurt the Republican Party's chances of winning the governorship in November", April 19, 1978; 17.
      - Called on the General Assembly to approve ethics legislation for all state employees, Harrisburg, PA, April 19, 1978; 18.
      - Schedule of campaign appearances for week of April 24 through April 29, 1978, April 21, 1978; 19.
      - Called for property tax reforms to help PA's elderly citizens stay in their own homes, Monroeville, PA, April 21, 1978; 20.
      - Proposed another measure aimed at helping PA's senior citizens stay in their own neighborhoods by phasing out of local property taxes as a means of financing public education, April 21, 1978; 21.
      - Pledged to reduce government red tape, to reform the tax system and to convene a Council on Economic Goals as the cornerstones of his economic revitalization effort for PA, April 25, 1978; 22.
      - Thornburgh unveiled his plan to convene a Council on Economic Goals, a coalition of business, labor, government and civic leaders, to provide guidance to governor in stimulating PA's economy, April 25, 1978; 23.
      - Public is invited to meet Dick Thornburgh at a reception April 29 in Towanda, PA, April 27, 1978; 24.
      - County Executive Russell D. Robison, the Veterans Political Action Council (VPAC), and the Pike County Republican Committee endorsed Thornburgh, April 28, 1978; 25.
      - Will kick off a "get out the vote" campaign in Western PA on April 29 with a tour of Pittsburgh's area shopping centers, April 29, 1978; 26.
      - Schedule of campaign appearances for week of May 2 through May 7, April 29, 1978; 27.
      - Was endorsed by Chester County District Attorney William H. Lamb, Malvern, PA, April 30, 1978; 28.
    - May-June, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 14)
      - York County Thornburgh for Governor Chairman Darwin Moyer today announced that May 6 has been declared "Thornburgh Day" in York County, May 1, 1978; 1.
      - Proposed that PA schools emphasize "competency-based education," requiring students to achieve prescribed levels of ability and skills as they pass from grade to grade, Hershey, PA, May 2, 1978; 2.
      - Announcement of Dick Thornburgh's proposals for improving PA's public schools and colleges, May 2, 1978; 3.
      - Pledged to support import policies that will help the domestic steel industry, Johnstown, PA, May 2, 1978; 4.
      - Pledged to work closely with PA's congressional delegation to ensure that Conrail maintains rail facilities and a high level of service in PA, Altoona, PA, May 2, 1978; 5.
      - Was endorsed by U.S. Senator John Heinz, Washington DCMay 3, 1978, 6.
      - News from Senator Heinz: Heinz endorses Thornburgh for PA Governor, May 3, 1978; 7.
      - Pledged to support import policies that will preserve jobs in the domestic steel industry, McKeesport, PA, May 4, 1978; 8.
      - Pledged to promote comprehensive land use planning and other measures aimed at preserving PA farmlands and announced members of his statewide Farmers Committee, Annville, PA, May 5, 1978; 9.
      - Was guest of honor at an event sponsored by the York County Republican Committee, York, PA, May 6, 1978; 10.
      - Schedule of campaign appearances for the week of May 8 through May 13, May 6, 1978; 11.
      - Called for stronger laws to control hardcore pornography, Philadelphia, PA, May 9, 1978; 12.
      - Endorsed by the Philadelphia Daily News, giving Thornburgh the most major PA newspaper endorsements of any Republican contender, May 10, 1978; 13.
      - Praised the National Rifle Association for taking a leadership role in putting to rest confusion and controversy over the gun control issue in this year's PA primary, May 10, 1978; 14.
      - Pledged that in his administration, the PA Department of Labor and Industry will exert greater efforts to counsel and help mentally and physically handicapped citizens find productive jobs, Pittsburgh, PA, May 10, 1978; 15.
      - Called for stronger laws to control hardcore pornography, Pittsburgh, PA, May 11, 1978; 16.
      - Pledged to commit his administration to flood recovery efforts in Cambria, Somerset and Indiana Counties, Johnstown, PA, May 12, 1978; 17.
      - Pledged to actively promote the proposed U.S. Steel plant in Northwestern PA, Erie, PA, May 13, 1978; 18.
      - Visited area nursing homes and stressed his intention to assure quality care for older citizens living in these residences, Pittsburgh, PA, May 14, 1978; 19.
      - Thornburgh will make a Mother's Day tour of three homes in Allegheny County, May 14, 1978; 20.
      - Pledged that in his administration, the PA Department of Labor and Industry will exert greater efforts to counsel and help mentally and physically handicapped citizens find productive jobs, Scranton, PA, May 15, 1978; 21.
      - Primary Campaign Finance Report, Harrisburg, PA, June 9, 1978; 22.
      - Fundraising dinner at Frank Morrow's residence, June 20, 1978; 23.
      - Release opposing bills politicizing the PA Fish and Game Commissions by giving the governor power to appoint the executive directors, June 23, 1978; 24.
      - Thornburgh opposed the third term proposed charter changes in Philadelphia, June 28, 1978; 25.
      - Announcement of John N. Scales as Chairman of State-wide Democrats for Thornburgh-Scranton Committee, June 29, 1978; 26.
    - July-August, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 15)
      - Called for PA Turnpike Commissioners to rescind their decision to impose high toll increases effective August 1, 1978, July 13, 1978; 1.
      - Lawyers' Luncheon honoring Dick Thornburgh and Bill Scranton, III will be held July 14 in Philadelphia, July 13, 1978; 2.
      - Attributed the closing of another Pittsburgh bridge for safety reasons to former Mayor Flaherty's failure to properly maintain the city's bridges, Pittsburgh, PA, July 17, 1978; 3.
      - Urged that the PA Crime Commission be made independent and supported various reforms for the new office of elected Attorney General, Pittsburgh, PA, July 17, 1978; 4.
      - Questioned role of Jacob Kassab, Governor Shapp's former Transportation Secretary, as fundraiser for Pete Flaherty, Harrisburg, PA, July 18, 1978; 5.
      - Called on Shapp to dismiss patronage secretary Sam Begler, Pittsburgh, PA, July 21, 1978; 6.
      - Will make major policy statement on state government on July 24, Philadelphia, PA, July 21, 1978; 7.
      - Thornburgh-Scranton propose a state constitutional amendment to limit PA's government spending (Spending Cap Amendment), Pittsburgh, PA, July 24, 1978; 8.
      - Thornburgh-Scranton administration would establish a PA Heritage Affairs and Advisory Commission to aid their administration, West Mifflin, PA, August 8, 1978; 9.
      - Thornburgh pledged that the Allegheny Valley Expressway would be completed during his administration, Pittsburgh, PA, August 14, 1978; 10.
      - Urged Governor Shapp to appoint a Special Prosecutor to investigate alleged widespread corruption in PennDOT, York, PA, August 17, 1978; 11.
      - Will participate as a player in the Phillies celebrity softball game at Veterans Stadium, August 18, 1978; 12.
      - Announced Farm and Rural Families for Thornburgh-Scranton Committee and outlined agricultural program, Centre Hall, PA, August 22, 1978; 13.
      - Pledged that his administration will promote tourism, Philadelphia, PA, August 23, 1978; 14.
      - Announced Ed Michaels as Chairman of Allegheny County Democrats for Thornburgh-Scranton, Pittsburgh, PA, August 24, 1978; 15.
      - Renewed his call to Governor Shapp to appoint a Special Prosecutor to investigate evidence of wide-spread corruption in PennDOT, Philadelphia, PA, August 25, 1978; 16.
      - Challenged Flaherty to debate, Pittsburgh, PA, August 29, 1978; 17.
      - Scranton charged that Democrat nominee Robert Casey's refusal to debate on TV was "cheating PA voters," Pittsburgh, PA, August 30, 1978; 18.
      - Release on financial disclosures, Philadelphia, PA, August 31, 1978; 19.
      - Joined in a student registration drive at Penn State's University Park Campus, State College, PA, August 31, 1978; 20.
    - September, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 16)
      - Release on Flaherty fundraising in the State Office Building, Philadelphia, PA, September 1, 1978; 1.
      - Announces his 12-point plan for keeping existing jobs and attracting new jobs in PA, Altoona, PA, September 5, 1978; 2.
      - Kicked off "Operation Waste Watchers" and cost-cutting proposals he will make for cutting waste in PA's state government, Pittsburgh, PA, September 7, 1978; 3.
      - Release on Shapp disallowing funds for Arsenal Family and Children's Center, Pittsburgh, PA, September 11, 1978; 4.
      - Outlined 7-point plan for "cleaning up" corruption in PA's General Assembly, Harrisburg, PA, September 12, 1978; 5.
      - Stated that the Democratic leadership in the state legislature had "demonstrated undisguised arrogance and contempt for the citizens of PA" by formally advising Democratic legislative candidates to ignore some constituents, September 14, 1978; 6.
      - Release on "International City" and Delaware Valley Regional Advisory Committee, Philadelphia, PA, September 14, 1978; 7.
      - Scranton charged that Casey is "hiding from voters" and called him the "invisible candidate," Philadelphia, PA, September 15, 1978; 8.
      - Release on Waste Watchers: paperwork and storage and microfilm, September 16, 1978; 9.
      - Launching petition drive in Southeast PA to gather support of Thornburgh-Scranton spending cap, Ardmore, PA, September 16, 1978; 10.
      - Sharply criticized Flaherty's 9-point platform for PennDOT and outlined Thornburgh-Scranton Allegheny Valley Expressway funding proposals, West Tarentum, PA, September 17, 1978; 11.
      - Scranton said that corruption and mismanagement flourishes in PA's liquor control system and pledged that the Thornburgh-Scranton administration would work to clean it up, Downingtown, PA, September 19, 1978; 12.
      - Branded Flaherty's proposed Constitutional amendment requiring referendum on budget disagreements as "phony, irresponsible and dangerous," Philadelphia, PA, September 20, 1978; 13.
      - Release on Flaherty's refusal to debate in major metropolitan-area televised debate, September 21, 1978; 14.
      - Reaffirmed his support for PA sportsmen and their concerns, Carlisle, PA, September 21, 1978; 15.
      - Extended best wishes for a happy and healthy New Year to members of the Jewish community, Pittsburgh, PA, September 21, 1978; 16.
      - Charged that Shapp proposal to divert lottery revenues to PIDA "amounts to a raid on senior citizen programs," Pittsburgh, PA, September 22, 1978; 17.
      - Waste Watcher: 25% of non-statutory boards and commissions could be abolished with savings of $588,000, Pittsburgh, PA, September 23, 1978; 18.
      - PA Council of Republican women presented Thornburgh with a broom to "arm him for a clean sweep" of State government's mismanagement and corruption, Hershey, PA, September 23, 1978; 19.
      - Urged General Assembly to pass tough ethics legislation requiring public officials to disclose personal finances, pass the Common Cause election reform bill, and abolish the senatorial scholarship system, Philadelphia, PA, September 24, 1978; 20.
      - Thornburgh charged that Flaherty's acceptance of contributions from present and former Shappp administration officials discredit his ability to clean up Harrisburg, September 26, 1978; 21.
      - Called for elimination of 2.2 percent state income tax on the gain realized from selling one's home, Pittsburgh, PA, September 26, 1978; 22.
      - Former U.S. Treasury Secretary William E. Simon will speak at fundraising dinner for Republican gubernatorial nominee Thornburgh on September 27 in Pittsburgh, September 27, 1978; 23.
      - Scranton said Thornburgh-Scranton administration would move to improve conditions on Soldiers and Sailors Home, Erie, PA, September 28, 1978; 24.
      - Commented on unauthorized campaign activities conducted by convicted racketeer Anthony Michael Grosso, Pittsburgh, PA, September 28, 1978; 25.
      - Second voluntary pre-election disclosure of Thornburgh-Scranton campaign contributions, Philadelphia, PA, September 30, 1978; 26.
    - October, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - Charged that Democratic senators had "deliberately emasculated" a package of anti-crime bills and pledged he would push hard for passage of an effective grand jury law, Philadelphia, PA, October 1, 1978; 1.
      - Opening of Coral Scranton's art show sponsored by the Greater Harrisburg Arts Council, Harrisburg, PA, October 1, 1978; 2.
      - Waste Watcher: thousands of dollars could be saved if state officials stopped promoting themselves at taxpayers' expense, Harrisburg, PA, October 1, 1978; 3.
      - Called on Mayor Frank L. Rizzo to stop using "racially inflammatory and divisive rhetoric" in his charter change campaign, Philadelphia, PA, October 3, 1978; 4.
      - Received endorsement from WCAU-TV (Channel 10), a CBS-affiliated television station and one of the largest television outlets in PA, Philadelphia, PA, October 3, 1978; 5.
      - Said that Flaherty's ties to the politics of Mayor Frank Rizzo and Shapp make Flaherty "unfit for the job of cleaning up Harrisburg," Philadelphia, PA, October 5, 1978; 6.
      - Pledged to put an end to "dumping" residents of state mental institutions into overcrowded and sub-standard housing and unprepared communities, Mt. Pocono, PA, October 6, 1978; 7.
      - Pledged that as governor he will appoint well-qualified persons to serve on the PA Fish and Game Commission, October 7, 1978; 8.
      - Former Governor William W. Scranton will make state-wide campaign swing this week on behalf of the Thornburgh-Scranton ticket, October 9, 1978; 9.
      - Former Governor William W. Scranton urged a vote for Dick Thornburgh, calling his Democratic opponent "utterly incapable of cleaning up Harrisburg," Pittsburgh, PA, October 10, 1978; 10.
      - Five leading Democrats endorsed Thornburgh-Scranton, Philadelphia, PA, October 10, 1978; 11.
      - Was presented with a state party platform today by platform co-chairmen Robert J. Butera and Martha Bell Schoeninger, Vice Chairman of the Republican State Committee, Harrisburg, PA, October 11, 1978; 12.
      - Scranton said that the Thornburgh-Scranton administration will work to provide increased student financial aid through the PA Higher Education Assistance Agency (PHEAA), Pittsburgh, PA, October 12, 1978; 13.
      - Accused Flaherty of "hypocrisy" in campaign statements following disclosures that he accepted donations from at least 11 Democratic county organizations, nine of Shapp's top "cronies" and $25,000 from a major union, October 14, 1978; 14.
      - Said his administration will crack down on fraud and abuse in the state welfare programs, October 15, 1978; 15.
      - Reaffirmed his opposition to proposed charter change in Philadelphia, Philadelphia, PA, October 16, 1978; 16.
      - Documented misrepresentations in Flaherty's television and radio commercials and demanded that Flaherty remove them from the air, Philadelphia, PA, October 17, 1978; 17.
      - Scranton said his opponent, Robert Casey, had demonstrated "incredible insensitivity to the problems of PA's handicapped children" with his recent remark about hearing disabled children, October 18, 1978; 18.
      - Former President Gerald Ford will speak at fundraising dinner for Thornburgh and Scranton on October 19 in Philadelphia, PA, October 18, 1978; 19.
      - The Philadelphia Federation of Sportsmen's Clubs endorsed Dick Thornburgh for Governor and Bill Scranton for Lieutenant Governor, Philadelphia, PA, October 18, 1978; 20.
      - Called on Flaherty to repudiate his running mate's recent statement in favor of cutting special education programs for hearing disabled children, Philadelphia, PA, October 19, 1978; 21.
      - Pledged to establish a "one-stop clearinghouse" to help persons who want to create new businesses, and jobs, in order to minimize red tape and paperwork, Pittsburgh, PA, October 21, 1978; 22.
      - Charged that Democrat Peter Flaherty's refusal to promise to end the corruption-ridden PennDOT patronage system "is further proof that Mr. Flaherty has no intention of cleaning up the mess in Harrisburg," Kittanning, PA, October 24, 1978; 23.
      - Pledged to enforce milk bonding regulations and, if necessary, introduce new legislation to protect farmers from drastic financial losses, Butler, PA, October 24, 1978; 24.
      - Charged that Flaherty's policies as Mayor of Pittsburgh will result in "a crushing tax increase for Pittsburghers," Pittsburgh, PA, October 25, 1978; 25.
      - Philadelphia Building and Construction Trades Council endorsed Thornburgh as "the only man who can bring jobs to PA," Philadelphia, PA, October 27, 1978; 26.
      - Five leading Pittsburgh Democrats today endorsed the Thornburgh-Scranton ticket, Allentown, PA, October 27, 1978; 27.
      - Said that he and Scranton will establish a PA Heritage Affairs and Advisory Commission to aid their administration, Philadelphia, PA, October 28, 1978; 28.
      - The Pittsburgh Post-Gazette and The Philadelphia Daily News endorsed Thornburgh and Scranton, Philadelphia, PA, October 28, 1978; 29.
      - Scranton said that Casey's disclosure that he is worth at least "a quarter of a million dollars shows that he deliberately misled PA voters when he said he could not afford to take time off from his jobs to campaign for office," Pittsburgh, PA, October 28, 1978; 30.
      - The Philadelphia Inquirer, The Philadelphia Bulletin and The Pittsburgh Press endorsed Thornburgh and Scranton, resulting in editorial support from every major newspaper in PA, Philadelphia, PA, October 29, 1978; 31.
      - Accepted the endorsement of Veterans Political Action Council of Allegheny County (VPAC) which represents over 225,000 veterans, Pittsburgh, PA, October 29, 1978; 32.
      - PA Federation of Teachers endorsed Thornburgh and Scranton, Philadelphia, PA, October 30, 1978; 33.
      - Thornburgh-Scranton was endorsed by the Association of PA State College and University Faculties, Philadelphia, PA, October 30, 1978; 34.
      - Surged ahead of Flaherty in South West PA, according to a telephone call-in poll taken yesterday by KQV Radio, Pittsburgh, PA, October 31, 1978; 35.
      - Released campaign's third voluntary, pre-election disclosure showing contributions of $1,289,266 through October 31st, Philadelphia, PA, October 31, 1978; 36.
    - November, 1978 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Released contributions of $1,000 or more received by the Thornburgh-Scranton campaign since the last voluntary, complete disclosure on October 31, November 1, 1978; 1.
      - Charged that the recent closing of another city-maintained bridge was a direct result of former Mayor Flaherty's failure to properly maintain the city's bridges, Pittsburgh, PA, November 1, 1978; 2.
      - Outlined his plans for senior citizens at Action Alliance of Senior Citizens, a coalition of 270 senior citizen clubs, Philadelphia, PA, November 1, 1978; 3.